<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SBOL Data Model Specification | The Synthetic Biology Open Language</title><link>/datamodel-specification/</link><atom:link href="/datamodel-specification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>SBOL Data Model Specification</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/images/logo.svg</url><title>SBOL Data Model Specification</title><link>/datamodel-specification/</link></image><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 3.0.1</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-3.0.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-3.0.1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Version 3.0.1 is an extension of version 3.0.0 data model to allow
flexibility and extendibility of the following: move declaration of
SBOL namespace from serialization to identifiers, change all
identifiers.org URLs to short form, add serialization recommendation,
use best practices in URI examples, change of logos, added compact
validation rules, add extension of SBOL classes to extension options,
improve complementary standards section, explain closure assumptions
and document composition implications, use RDF cardinality
terminology, add combinatorial derivation &amp;amp; validation rules amongst
other fixes and updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Version 3.0.1 of SBOL was published on October 27, 2021&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 3.0.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-3.0.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-3.0.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Condenses and simplifies previous versions of SBOL, separates sequence features from part/sub-part relationships, renames ComponentDefinition/Component to Component/SubComponent, merges Component and Module classes, ensuring consistency between data model and ontology terms, extends the means to define and reference SubComponents, refines requirements on object URIs, enables graph-based serialization, moves Systems Biology Ontology (SBO) for Component types, makes all sequence associations explicit, makes interfaces explicit, generalizes SequenceConstraints into a general structural Constraint class, and expands the set of allowed constraints.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 2.3.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-2.3.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-2.3.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Includes means of succinctly representing sequence modifications, an
extension to support organization and attachment of experimental data,
and an extension for describing numerical parameters of design
elements. The new version also includes specifying types of synthetic
biology activities, unambiguous locations for sequences with multiple
encodings, and refinement of a number of validation rules.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 2.2.1</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-2.2.1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-2.2.1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Clarification on ontology terms on roles for proteins and small
molecules, refining a number of validation rules, and illustrating a
design for combinatorial derivations using Prov-O.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 2.2.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-2.2.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-2.2.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Version 2.2.0 introduces new classes for representing combinatorial
genetic designs, physical implementations of genetic designs, and
attachments to external files. It also adds best practices for using
existing classes to encode provenance for the Design-Build-Test-Learn
cycle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Version 2.2.0 of SBOL was published on April 2, 2018.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 2.1.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-2.1.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-2.1.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>A backwards-compatible release extending the data model and updating ontology terms and best practices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 2.1.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-2.0.1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-2.0.1/</guid><description>&lt;p>An updated version of SBOL 2.0 data model to refine validation rules.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 2.0.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-2.0.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-2.0.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>An extension of version 1.1 data model to allow flexibility and
extendibility of the following: Represent non-DNA structural
components of a biological design; Describe the behavioral aspects of
a biological design; Associate structure and function to a design;
Support rich annotation of biological designs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 1.1.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-1.1.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-1.1.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Version 1.1.0 of the SBOL core data model is limited to the
description of discrete segments of DNA, called DNA components. To
remove ambiguity when specifying the design of synthetic DNA, the
information about DNA components is structured. DNA components
described using the SBOL core data model may have an associated DNA
sequence, or may be left as abstract descriptions. This flexibility
allows for the description of DNA component designs which have not yet
been realized, as well as those which are specific implementations of
that design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Data Model Version 1.0.0</title><link>/datamodel-specification/version-1.0.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/datamodel-specification/version-1.0.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Define the vocabulary that contain a set of preferred terms and the
core data model composed of a common computational representation, to
enable the electronic exchange of information describing DNA
components used in synthetic biology.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>