<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SBOL Visual Specification | The Synthetic Biology Open Language</title><link>/visual-specification/</link><atom:link href="/visual-specification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>SBOL Visual Specification</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/images/logo.svg</url><title>SBOL Visual Specification</title><link>/visual-specification/</link></image><item><title>SBOL Visual Version 3.0.0</title><link>/visual-specification/version-3.0.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/visual-specification/version-3.0.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>The major difference between SBOL Visual 3 and SBOL Visual 2 is that
diagrams and glyphs are defined with respect to the SBOL 3 data model
rather than the SBOL 2 data model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A byproduct of this change is that the use of dashed undirected lines
for subsystem mappings has been removed. Until a decision is made
about how to represent constraints, the specification is mute on both
constraints and dashed undirected lines, which means that it is
acceptable to use them, if desired, as an annotation indicating
identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, collection of glyphs has been modified as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The deprecated Insulator glyph and “shmoo” Macromolecule alternative
glyph have been removed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deprecated BioPAX alternatives to SBO terms for molecular species
glyphs have been removed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The changes for this release were approved as SEP V024.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Visual Version 2.3.0</title><link>/visual-specification/version-2.3.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/visual-specification/version-2.3.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>SBOL Visual 2.3 provides a simple and flexible language for diagrams
of genetic systems and design, including both structure (e.g., nucleic
acid sequence features) and function (e.g., regulatory interactions
and reactions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SBOL Visual 2.3 enhances the prior SBOL Visual 2.2 standard as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Adds higher-level &amp;ldquo;interactions with interactions&amp;rdquo;, such as an
inducer molecule stimulating a repression interaction&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Binding with a nucleic acid backbone can be shown by overlapping
glyphs, as with other molecular complexes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Recommends using polypeptide region glyph to show 2A sequences&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adds new &amp;ldquo;unspecified interaction&amp;rdquo; glyph for visualizing
interactions whose nature is unknown&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deprecates &amp;ldquo;insulator&amp;rdquo; glyph in favor of new &amp;ldquo;inert DNA spacer&amp;rdquo; glyph&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>SBOL Visual Version 2.2.0</title><link>/visual-specification/version-2.2.0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/visual-specification/version-2.2.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>SBOL Visual 2.2 provides a simple and flexible language for diagrams
of genetic systems and design, including both structure (e.g., nucleic
acid sequence features) and function (e.g., regulatory interactions
and reactions).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SBOL Visual 2.2 enhances the prior SBOL Visual 2.1 standard as
follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Grounding for molecular species glyphs is changed from BioPAX to SBO
(BioPAX terms are retained as deprecated alternatives).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New glyphs are added for introns and polypeptide regions (e.g., protein domains).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The macromolecule glyph often confused with yeast is deprecated, and a new glyph for proteins added&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Small polygons are recommended as alternative glyphs for simple chemicals.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>SBOL Visual Version 2.1.0</title><link>/visual-specification/version-2.1.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/visual-specification/version-2.1.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>SBOL Visual 2.1 provides a simple and flexible language for diagrams
of genetic systems and design, including both structure (e.g., nucleic
acid sequence features) and function (e.g., regulatory interactions
and reactions). SBOL Visual 2.1 enhances the prior SBOL Visual 2.0
standard with the addition of methods for showing modular structure
and mappings between elements of a system, and new glyphs for
indicating genomic context (e.g., integration into a plasmid or
genome) and for stop codons. Additionally, interactions arrows were
modified such that they can split or join, with the glyph at the split
or join indicating either superposition or a chemical process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Visual Version 2.0.0</title><link>/visual-specification/version-2.0.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/visual-specification/version-2.0.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>A diagram language and collection of symbols that can be used to
graphically depict a genetic design and its functional
interactions. SBOL Visual 2.0 builds on the prior SBOL Visual 1.0
standard by expanding diagram syntax to include functional
interactions and molecular species, making the relationship between
diagrams and the SBOL data model explicit, supporting families of
symbol variants, clarifying a number of requirements and best
practices, and significantly expanding the collection of diagram
glyphs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SBOL Visual Version 1.0.0</title><link>/visual-specification/version-1.0.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/visual-specification/version-1.0.0/</guid><description>&lt;p>A set of symbols that can be used to graphically depict functional
information encoded by nucleic acid sequences. Each symbol in the set
has three components: a shape, a display name, and a definition.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>